Welcome back to Movie Recaps. Today I will show you an action thriller
film from 2008 titled Terra Nova. Spoilers ahead. Watch out
and take care. On the cold hills of a deserted island, Zhilin is trying
to find a safe spot to camp. He walks for miles until he slips and
falls into a freezing river. But after floating away for a while, he manages
to climb out and continue his journey. When he gets too tired to keep going,
he stops to rest against a big rock, grabs a flower to eat,
begins thinking back to how all this started. Zhilin is in jail for
life for the assassination of six men when one afternoon he's taken to see the
prison governor who asks him what he dreams of. He isn't the only person going
through this. Various of his fellow prisoners are also being called to the governor's office
and are asked the same question. Moriake says he wants to see the sea.
Yakut wants to witness the war against China. Obizyanka won't speak.
Obezyan wants to work in this prison and be a governor. Tolya wants to follow
the progress of the space station, and Sipa wants to see women again. But Thlin's
answer is never shown. The governor tells them they've been selected to be transferred to
a penal colony and shortly afterward all prisoners are boarded into a ship,
just like in the actual prison. The prisoners are divided into groups
and put into cells, although Obezyan acts like he is the boss and even kills
a man to take his bed. When the hatch is finally closed and the boat
takes off, the prisoners start panicking, thinking this has all been a trick to let
them die at sea. As the men begin getting violent, Billen remembers a conversation he
had with Sipa back in prison. Sipa has some severe mental issues and would always
draw on the wall and talk nonsense. But that day he mentioned heaven and hell,
not having any seats left and a third purgatory like place being prepared for people
like them. Juliane had thought it was more of his usual nonsense back then,
but he's starting to see the merits of it now. After a while everyone calms
down and tries to spend the trip chit chatting and eating. But in the middle
of the journey, a gang escapes from one of the cells looking for their compatriot.
Obezyan pretends to negotiate at first only to kill the man they're looking
for, causing a riot to start. Prisoners on both sides begin hitting and killing each
other through the bars, except for Stary, an old man that stays behind praying the
fight doesn't last long, though. The guards quickly arrive and after stopping them with a
warning shot, they throw a sleeping gas grenade to knock them all out. Eventually,
they make it to a deserted island where the prisoners are put into numbered handcuffs
and left at the beach so they can listen to what Mr. Olufsen and Marta,
the heads of the Terra Nova project, have to say. Since the death penalty has
become illegal in all countries, prisons have been running out of space to hold such
a large number of criminals, which is why the Russian government has offered this land
to start this project, funded by some international organizations. Starting today,
the prisoners are colonists living under their protection, and everything they need to survive is
being provided, including food that should last three months. A satellite will be watching
them all the time, and there also are some communication buoys around. They have the
possibility to take a boat to one of them to press the red button and
say what they need. If a green light appears, that means the request has been
accepted. Obezyan isn't happy about the idea of being recorded 24 7,
so he throws a big rock in protest, but the guards quickly make him stand
back with some warning shots. Marta clarifies that the buoys can also be used to
ask to leave the project by saying their name and the reason why they want
to leave. If they do, they'll be returned to prison. By putting the
buoys on the sea instead of on the beach, they make sure that the decision
is thought twice before risking getting on a boat. Before leaving, the guards
drop a bunch of keys on the sand, explaining they are numbered to match their
handcuffs. The prisoners rush towards them and start fighting over them, while Dylan
and Sipa stay safely behind, only grabbing the keys that the others drop.
Stary also decides to stay behind and watch. How a gang forms a
line around the keys to keep their rivals out, and a group goes to the
crates the guards left to pick up some weapons and attack the crowd with them.
Eventually, Ali's gang takes control of the situation.
Ali gets a jacket and good shoes for himself and Stary before choosing a man
to send out on the boat. But as soon as he grabs someone, the group
takes the chance to attack and the fight starts again. Dozens of men die in
the fight. Moriah kills Ali with a rock, Obezyan kills Stary also with a rock,
and the three men that get on a boat to reach the buoy fall to
the sea and die, drowning. All the remaining prisoners go to the warehouse and begin
distributing the supplies, and Obezyan takes advantage of the tools found to get his
Cuffs open by force, Dylan packs a bunch of supplies in a bag and grabs
himself a jacket while listening to Sipa say there is no way the food will
last three months. Then he leaves the area to survive on his own and hopefully
find a way out of the island. Taking us back to the beginning of the
story, Zhilin explores the island until he finds an area with no snow and a
rocky formation that will provide some shelter. So he decides to sit there while looking
at a picture of his family that he's kept hidden in his prison uniform.
He misses them terribly and falls asleep with tears in his eyes.
Sometime later, he wakes up when he hears some squealing. Turns out the supplies
were filled with rodents and they are now eating through his food and bag.
When it starts raining, Zhilin finds shelter under the rock formation he saw before,
getting a fire, going for warmth and heating some water. After it stops raining,
he catches a bird and roasts it over the fire. That's when Sipa finds him.
As he chit chats with him. He tries to steal his knife, but Zhilin sees
him and takes it back. Sipa offers some salt he had with him and his
help in exchange for some meat, which Ziling accepts. So Sipa goes to pick up
more wood and sees the family picture on Dylan hung on the rocks, which makes
him blow a kiss at Dylan's wife. Afterward, they share the bird, and when they're
done eating, Sipa walks to the edge of the cliff explaining he doesn't jump because
he's too afraid. He asks Zhilin why he won't die either, and Zhilin explains it's
because of his family. They're dead and he wants to be buried next to them,
which can't happen if he dies on the island. The two men fall asleep,
and when Zhilin wakes up, he finds Sipa has stolen the picture to use it
as inspiration for his debauchery. Furious, Zhilin beats him up and pushes
him off the cliff. But Sipa doesn't die because he doesn't fall into the ocean.
He drops on a hill right underneath. But even after this disagreement,
the two of them travel together. As they explore the island, Sipa easily amuses
himself with the trash he finds in the water while Zhilin tries to fish.
But the only living being they find in the water is some sort of aquatic
centipede, which freaks Sipa out. While looking around, Zhilin is shocked
to suddenly find part of a seaplane among the rocks. It only takes going a
bit farther up the hill to find the entire plane, which gives him a bit
of hope because he used to be a pilot and would be able to fly
it. However, two men aren't enough to move it, so for now they go back
to their shelter. Dylan starts a fire with some matches he had grabbed at the
warehouse, but there's something in them that creates a very toxic smoke. He moves
away from the fire and drags a sleeping Sipa with him, who at first won't
wake up. It takes a few shakes from Zhilin for him to finally regain consciousness,
but his mouth only continues to spout nonsense, and Zhilin realizes the cold will kill
them any minute now. The two men decide to go back to the base and
see if they can steal some coal. Back in the base, life hasn't been easy
for everyone. Obezyan and his gang are in control and keeping a routine while
sharing the supplies, and Obezyan even asks them to call him Governor. But they keep
anyone that isn't in their team inside the barracks. They only allow them to come
out to have a walk in an enclosed area similar to real prisons, while Estonets
yells at them from the watchtower. When they're sent back, they need to run because
whoever is last gets killed to be used as food. Later, Dylan and Sipa manage
to reach the coal box and find the remains of a fire. After walking for
so long, they're almost freezing, so they can't help laying down next to the fire
and falling asleep. But Sipa wakes up quickly when he hears some noises. The gang
is coming over with their latest prisoner for roasting. He runs to hide behind a
rock, but Zhilin is still out there, so he comes back out to rescue him,
but he isn't fast enough and Obezyan's men find them and capture them. The two
of them are taken back to base, where Obezyan tries to decide what their punishment
will be for having run away with supplies when they arrived. Yakut tries to remind
them that they were on their side during the ship fight, causing Estonets to insult
him for trying to meddle. Yakut replies by hitting him, and this causes the whole
gang to team up to hit him in return, earning Yakut a place in the
barracks with Zhilin and Sipa. They walk around for a while, and when Estonets announces
it's time to return, Zhilin stays behind, but Sipa comes back from him
and drags him inside with him. They can only watch as the last standing man
is captured and Tied to a pole, begging for some water as his last wish.
So. So Sipa takes pity on him and brings a cup to his lips before
he is killed. Later, before going to sleep, the group discusses the possibility of rebelling.
They're unsure because it may be dangerous, but Sram convinces them is worth trying.
The next morning, Tolya shows Obaziankat that he's installed a secret trap
in his workshop to catch any potential thieves. After the group takes his daily walk,
Estonets tries to get them back inside to get the usual game going, but only
two men run. The rest stand back and come together while Yakut throws a rock
at Estonets to shut him up. Dylan walks up to Abezyan and offers him a
if he lets them go to the buoy and ask for food, he'll tell him
the location of the plane he found. Obezyan accepts and opens the gate to let
them out, while Tolya and Zhilin go with two other men on the boat.
Obezyan asks his men if they know anything about Zhilin, and that's how he learns
he was a pilot, that his family died in a plane crash and he went
to jail for killing flight dispatchers at the airport with a rifle. This crime was
classified as murder in a state of severe emotional agitation, which Obezyan thinks means
Zhilin has a guilty conscience. As soon as the boat is far enough, he orders
the group to go back to the barracks, canceling his deal. Yakut tries to confront
them, but he's immediately killed, so Obezyan grabs one more man before declaring
the game is on again. The group can only run back to the barracks since
a fight would be a very bad idea because Obezyan's men are armed. Meanwhile,
at sea, one of the men falls off the boat, but they catch him just
in time and drag him back up. Tolya reaches the buoy and asks for help,
but it's broken and not even his tools will help. They go back to the
shore and Zhilin tells Obezyan that food is on its way. But Obezyan doesn't believe
him because there wasn't a green light of confirmation. Tolya reminds him of the existence
of the plane, but Obezyan doesn't believe that's true either. But it inspires Obizyanka to
move around with his arms open like one. Obezyan finds this distracting and
grabs him by the neck, so Tolya uses the chance to come at him from
behind and kill him. Two other members of his group. Amurbek and Ertsonov
kill the rest of their gang and watch Estonets run away before they can catch
him as well. They ask Zhilin what to do next, and he asks them to
free the men from the barracks because he swears food is coming and they just
didn't see the light because it was broken. The men are skeptical about this and
remind him now they have plenty of bodies to feed on later, but Tolya thinks
they should be buried. Zhilin reminds him about the plane as well, so Amurbek and
Erzonov finally accept. They free the prisoners and tell them they'll be waiting a few
days for the food to arrive, but they won't be using each other as food
anymore, so everyone needs to stay calm and cooperate. They'll also send a group to
rescue the plane, which they'll put in a hangar they'll build and slowly repair it
to escape later. Suddenly, Sipa interrupts their plans, claiming there's no
satellite, while writing an SOS message using sand and three bodies.
Sometime later, Estonets returns to the base and because of
the new rules that say they need to keep the peace, they decide to ignore
what he's done to them for now and share their food with him anyway.
Zhilin guides a group of men towards the plane and their moods greatly increase when
they see he's been telling the truth. Together they take it apart for easier transport
and carry the pieces back to base. Eventually, Marta arrives
at the island with a bunch of guards. They use gas to keep the men
away, but they do allow Villain come to talk to her and discuss the list
of things they've requested. She's confused on why they're asking for gas and he
explains it's for the generators, which are supposed to be wind powered, but they don't
work during the polar night. In truth, they want the gas for the plane.
Dylan takes the chance to ask why they didn't answer Sipa's SOS message
and Marta explains their satellite is of the infrared. They see heat so
they can locate people in stoves, but not words. She also wants to know what
people were doing so far away from the base some days ago, and he tells
her they were fishing. They don't believe him because there's no fish in the area,
so he lies again and tells them they've been eating those centipede like creatures,
which she finds very shocking. They also want to know how many of the original
206 colonists are left, which Zhilin finds suspicious because they should be able
to tell with their satellite. He tells them 87 are left and many are sick,
but nobody wants to abandon the project and return to jail. Before Thylen leaves,
Marte tells him he has the right to one personal request. So he gives her
a few sheets of paper, asking her to provide the group well. Once the guards
have left the new supplies, Zhilin and his men try the gas in the plane
hidden in the hangar and happily confirm it does work. Afterward, they watch a new
group of American prisoners arrive as the guards and Marta leave the island. These prisoners
have a leader too, a very large man that Zhilin tries to shake hands with.
The man doesn't take it. In fact, he hits Zhilin, which triggers
a fight between both sides. The encounter is brutal and nobody hesitates to
go for the kill, so Sipa drags Zhilin with him to hide him in the
workshop. One of the Americans tries to follow them, but he falls on Tolya's
trap and instantly dies. Arzonov goes up against the American leader and gets overpowered,
but before he can get killed, Amarbek cuts in and kills the big man instead
as the buildings around them catch on fire. All this is being watched by the
heads of the project. When they realize the situation is finally out of control
and that over 40% of the colony has been killed, Marta calls the central office
and is told to proceed with Code Naked island, which sends a bunch of guards
to the island that shoots all the reminder prisoners while Marta burns Zhilin's letters.
Luckily, a few men are still alive, thanks to having hidden in the mountains
or the hangar. Zhilin, Siepa, Ertsonov and Tolya.
Together they push the plane out. But when they're about to board it, Sipa tells
them goodbye and runs to the hill so he can jump into the ocean.
Not afraid anymore. The remaining trio gets in the plane and Thylin manages
to make it take off safely. Although the guards shoot at them on the way,
his two companions die, but Zhilin isn't hit by the bullets, so he
flies away into his freedom. Make sure to subscribe and turn on notifications
so you can watch more videos like this. Thanks for watching.